today we're going to try something
今天我们要 尝试 一些
different we're going to try a
不同我们会尝试一个
conversation we have Lisa Feldman
我们有Lisa Feldman的谈话
Barrett with us she is a university
巴雷特和我们在一起她是一所大学
distinguished professor of psychology at
杰出的心理学教授
Northeastern University director of the
东北大学主任
interdisciplinary affective Science
跨学科的情感 科学
Laboratory author of the new amazing
实验室作者新的惊人
book how emotions are made the secret
预定情绪如何成为秘密
life of the brain she studies emotion
她研究情感的大脑生活
human emotion from social psychological
社会心理学中的人类情感
cognitive science and neuroscience
认知科学和神经科学
perspectives and so I think our
观点， 所以我认为我们的
conversation may help us gain intuition
谈话可以帮助我们获得直觉
about how we instill emotional life into
关于我们 如何 将情感生活灌输到
future artificial intelligence systems
未来的人工智能系统
as Josh Tenenbaum gave you a shout out
作为乔希·特南鲍姆给你留言 了
on Tuesday and said that if you want to
在星期二 说，如果你想
understand how to create artificial
了解如何 创建人工
general intelligence systems from an
一般情报系统来自
engineering perspective we should study
工程视角我们应该研究
the human brain so with that let's have
人类的大脑就这样，让我们​​拥有
some fun let me start with the curveball
一些乐趣 让我从 曲线球 开始
to conjure up an image of emotion have
变出 情感 都 的形象
you ever cried while watching a movie
你一直在看电影时哭过
that you remember and what movie was it
你记得哪部电影是什么？
I've cried during lots of movies
我在很多电影中哭过
let me think the last time I cried
让我 想起 我 最后一次 哭泣
actually here's an interesting thing
实际上这是一件有趣的事情
when I'm speaking about when I'm giving
当我在谈论我什么时候给予
an academic talk I sometimes will talk
我有时会谈论学术谈话
about a study that we did where we had
关于我们所做 的研究
people watch films and we have them
人们看电影，我们有他们
watch the most evocative clips of films
观看最令人回味的电影剪辑
and there's several clips that are
并且有几个片段
really powerful and
真的很强大
a couple of them every time I talk about
每次我谈论时都会有几个
them I'm gonna try not to cry now every
他们我会尽量 不要 哭了 每
time I talk about them I'm describing
时间我谈论他们我正在描述
for the audience what subjects are
对于观众什么 科目 是
seeing one of the clips is from a movie
看到其中一个片段来自电影
called Sophie's Choice does anyone know
叫苏菲的选择 ，没有 人知道
this film raise your hand if you know
如果你知道，这部电影举起你的手
this film so we show this is a film
这部电影让 我们展示这是一部电影
about a woman who is forced in a
关于一个被逼入的女人
concentration camp to choose which of
集中营选择哪个
her children will die in the gas
她的孩子会死在气里
chambers and so I'm already you know
房间， 所以我已经知道了
like if you were if I had a heart rate
就好像你 有心率一样
monitor and respiration monitor you
监测和呼吸 监测你
would see them like it's a really
会看到他们就像是真的
powerful scene Meryl Streep is Sophie
强大的场景梅丽尔 斯特里普是索菲
and it's very very evocative we have we
我们拥有 它，这 非常令人回味
also show there's a scene from a film
还展示了一部电影的场景
with Susan Sarandon
与苏珊萨兰登
who is dying of breast cancer and she
谁死于乳腺癌和她
has to tell her 12 year old daughter
不得不告诉她 12岁的 女儿
that she's dying
她 快死了
so there's another scene also that um
嗯 ，还有另一个场景
that I find very compelling and you use
我觉得非常引人注目， 你 使用
these scenes to listen to motion as part
这些场景听取动作的一部分
of experiments we do yeah and in fact I
我们做的实验是的，事实上我
was just giving a presentation to the
只是给了一个演示文稿
Supreme Judicial Court of Massachusetts
马萨诸塞州最高司法法院
on implicit bias and to start the you
在隐含的偏见和 启动 你
know they want to understand the
知道他们想要了解
neuroscience of implicit bias and
隐性偏见的神经科学
whether or not they should be crafting
他们是否应该制作
jury instructions for juries to be aware
陪审团指示陪审团要注意
of implicit bias and to open the
隐性偏见和打开
discussion I showed them a clip from a
讨论中，我向他们展示了 从 剪辑
film that was filmed I you know almost
这 是 我 拍过 电影 ，你知道 几乎
20 years ago actually called a time to
20年前实际上是时候了
kill a scene where Matthew McConaughey
杀死Matthew McConaughey 的场景
is this kind of he's his closing
这是他的结束
statements in a case where he is
在他是的情况下的陈述
defending an african-american man who
捍卫一个 非洲裔美国人
murdered two European American men who
谋杀了两名欧洲裔美国人
raped his twelve-year-old daughter and
强奸了他十二岁的女儿和
so the scene is he's this completely
这样的情景是他这个 完全
pathetic lawyer until the end when he
可怜的律师直到 他结束的时候
masters this fantastic defense basically
掌握这个梦幻般的防守基本上
of this man on trial for you know
你知道 ，这个男人正在接受审判
basically avenging his daughter's death
基本上是为了复活女儿的死亡
and that one I hadn't seen that for 20
那个我20年没见过的那个
years that film and it brought me to
电影带给我的那几年
tears actually it's just a really
眼泪真的只是一个真的
powerful powerful scene and it's it just
强大的强大场景，它就是它
really punches you in the stomach you
真的在 你肚子里打你
just can't help but just experience the
只是忍不住 只是体验 一下
weight of racism in that in that room
在那个房间里种族主义的重量
and the brilliance of the closing
和闭合的光辉
argument to sort of puncture through it
通过它进行穿刺的论点
basically right
基本上对
okay so experience so one of the things
好吧所以经历这样的事情之一
you talk a lot and you're working in
你说了很多，而且你在 工作
your book is the difference in the
你的书与众不同
experience of emotion the expression of
情感体验表达
emotion so what our what's our biggest
情感 所以我们最大的是什么
misconception about emotion for folks
人们对情感的误解
who haven't considered
谁没有考虑过
have only considered emotions at a
我只考虑过 情绪
surface level I would say one common
表面水平我会 说一个常见的
misconception is that you can look at
误解是 你可以看一下
someone's face and read their emotion
某人的脸，并阅读他们的情感
the way you read words on a page that
你在页面上阅读文字 的方式
everyone around the world when they're
他们在 世界各地的每个人
feeling angry they scowl when they're
当他们感到愤怒 时，他们会感到愤怒
feeling happy they smile when they're
幸福感受他们的微笑时，他们
feeling sad that they frown the way that
他们皱眉的感觉很伤心
I'm saying it sounds preposterous and it
我说这听起来很荒谬，它
is preposterous
是荒谬的
but unfortunately that is actually what
但不幸的是，这 实际上是什么
people a lot of people believe and tech
人们很多人都相信和科技
companies around the world spend
世界各地的公司都在消费
tremendous amounts of money and you know
你 知道 ， 这笔 巨额 资金
in the investment of some of the most
在一些 最投资
creative people on this planet trying to
有创意的人在这个星球上 试图
build a motion detection systems when
建立运动检测系统时
really what they're building our
真的是他们正在建设我们的
excellent systems for reading facial
优秀的面部阅读系统
movements which have no intrinsic
没有内在的运动
emotional meaning
情感意义
I mean sometimes facial movements
我的意思是有时面部动作
communicate emotion but many times they
沟通情感，但他们很多次
don't so people scowl for many reasons
不要因为很多原因而使人们皱眉
they scowl when they're concentrating
当他们集中注意力时，他们会皱眉
they scowl sometimes when they're sad
他们伤心的时候有时皱着眉头
they even can scowl when they're happy
当他们开心时，他们甚至可以皱眉
people smile when they're angry they
人们微笑，当他们生气 ，他们
smile when they're sad they don't just
微笑，当他们难过，他们不 只是
smile when they're happy they sometimes
当他们有时快乐时微笑
smile to indicate to send commute you
微笑表示发送通勤你
know a social message that has something
知道有某事的社交信息
to do with emotion and so the idea that
与情感有关的想法
there's one Universal facial expression
有一个通用的面部表情
for example for each emotion is just
例如，每种 情绪都是恰当的
there's no strong scientific evidence
没有强有力的 科学证据
for that claim so how is emotion created
对于那个主张，如何创造情感
them because we nevertheless feel like
他们因为我们感觉像
we're observing emotional we're
我们正在观察情绪
communicating with others so how does
与他人沟通的方式如何
emotion the creation of emotion change
情绪创造 情感变化
in the presence of others the does the
在其他人面前，他们会这样做
audience change the display of emotion
观众改变了 情感的表现
is that essentially the message
这 本质上就是信息
well emotions are not displayed I would
好吧情绪不会显示我会
say right so basically you and I are
说得对，所以基本上你和我
having conversation right now
现在正在 交谈
and part of what you know my brain is
你知道我的大脑的一部分
doing is it's guessing make making
这是在 猜测制作
educated guesses about what your facial
关于你 的面部 猜测
movements mean so right now you have a
动作意味着现在你有一个
slight smile on your face not exactly a
脸上的微笑并不完全是一个
smirk but and so you know say Russian by
傻笑， 但所以你知道说俄语
the way so we're not allowed to show any
所以我们不允许 展示任何方式
emotion you know I have a friend of mine
情感 你知道 我有 我 的一个朋友
who is Russian who told me and she when
谁是俄罗斯谁 告诉我和她 什么时候
she moved to this country actually I've
她居然搬到了这个国家
had several friends tell me this that
有好几个 朋友告诉 我这个
their cheeks hurt for a year for how
他们的脸颊伤了一年怎么样
much smiling they had to do I have also
多微笑，他们不得不这样做我 也有
a friend from the Netherlands who moved
感动荷兰的朋友
here who told me the same thing her face
在这里谁告诉我同样的事情她的脸
ached for how much smiling she did and
因为她做了多少微笑而感到痛苦
in Bulgaria they haven't apparently like
在保加利亚他们显然不喜欢
a name for you know the pervasive
一个名字，你知道无处不在
American smile kind of like a not
美国的笑容有点像不是
flattering name for how much Americans
恭维美国人的名字
smile but basically you when you look at
微笑， 但基本上你看的时候
someone's face you're making a guess
某人的脸， 你猜对了
about how they feel and although you
关于他们的感受，尽管你
yourself are focused on their face to
你自己专注于他们的脸
you it feels as if that's where all the
你就觉得好像 这就是所有
information is your brain is actually
信息是你的大脑实际上
taking in the entire sensory array so
因此，接受整个 感官阵列
it's taking in also you know the sound
它也吸收了你 的声音
of the person's voice and the person's
这个人的声音和人的声音
body posture and the dynamic temporal
身体姿势和动态时间
changes in all of those signals to make
在所有这些信号的变化， 使
sense of things it's not you're not
事物的感觉不是你不是
really the face is not a lighthouse it's
真的，脸不是灯塔
not a beacon that just displays
不是只显示的灯塔
somebody's internal state in an
某个人的内部状态
obligatory way nevertheless there's some
尽管如此，还是必须采取一些措施
signal there of course and so what are
当然有信号，那是什么
what would you say as far as I
就你而言，你会怎么说？
understand there's no good answer yet
明白还没有好的答案
from sciences what are the basic
从科学到底是什么基础
building blocks of emotion well I
情感的 基石 以及我
wouldn't say that there's no good answer
不会说 没有好的 答案
from science I would say scientists
从科学我会说科学家
disagree I think it's very clear what
不同意我觉得很明显是什么
the building plugs are
建筑插头是
but you know in one way or another if
但你知道的是这样或那样
you look back all the way to ancient
你一直回顾 古代
Greece you can see that there are two
希腊你可以看到有两个
kinds of views of emotion that have been
各种各样的情感观
battling it out for millennia one is the
与它争斗了 几千年的一个是
idea that you have I will give you the
你有这个想法我会给你的
modern versions of these views but they
这些观点的现代版本，但他们
really do have a very long history one
确实有很长的历史 中
is the idea that you are born with
是，你是天生的想法
circuits in your brain that are pre what
你脑中的 电路 是什么
you know kind of pre-wired for emotion
你知道有点情感的预先布线
so that everybody around the world is
因此， 世界 各地的 每个人都
born with an anger circuit a fear
生来就有一种愤怒的恐惧
circuit a sadness circuit a happiness
悲伤电路是一种 幸福
circuit some other circuits too you have
你也有其他一些电路
them we all have them all neurotypical
他们我们都有他们所有的神经典型
brains have them and actually other
大脑有它们， 实际上是其他的
animals have them too and the idea is
动物也有它们，这个想法 是
that when you know one of these circuits
当你知道 这些电路 中的 一个
is triggered you have an emotional
触发你有情感
response which is obligatory so you have
你有 必要的回应
a very stereotypic
非常陈规定型
your breathing changes in a stereotypic
你的呼吸在刻板印象中发生了变化
way your you know heart rate changes
你知道心率变化的方式
your the chemicals in your body change
你体内的化学物质会发生变化
in a particular way you make a
以一种特殊的方式你做一个
particular facial expression and you are
特别的面部表情，你
have a propensity to make a particular
倾向于做出一个特定的
action like you you know attack and
像你这样的行动你知道攻击和
anger and you run in fear or you freeze
愤怒，你恐惧或你冻结
in fear and then there's another view
在恐惧中然后还有另一种观点
which says well there are some basic
这说得有一些基本的
kind of ingredients or building blocks
一种成分或构建块
that the human mind or the human brain
人类的头脑或人类的大脑
now people talk about the brain now
现在人们谈论 大脑吧
there are some basic ingredients that
有 一些基本的成分 ，
your brain uses and it uses them to make
你的大脑使用它并使用 它们来 制作
every kind of mental event that you
你所做的每一种心理事件
experience and every action that you
经验和你的每一个动作
take the recipes are what are unique the
采取的食谱是什么独特的
ingredients are common right just like
成分很常见就像
you can take flour and water and salt
你可以吃面粉，水和盐
and you can make a whole bunch of
你可以做出一大堆
different recipes with them some of
不同的食谱 与他们一些
which aren't even food like glue in a
它甚至不像胶水 那样的 食物
similar way the idea is that your brain
类似的方式， 这个 想法是 你的大脑
has some kind of all-purpose capacities
拥有某种通用能力
and it can it puts these ingredients
它可以把这些成分
together and it makes emotion as you
在一起， 它让 你 感情用事
need them on the spot and you don't have
需要他们当场， 你没有
one anger you have a whole repertoire of
一个愤怒，你有一个完整的曲目
anger
愤怒
you don't have one sadness you have a
你没有一个悲伤
whole repertoire of sadness and if you
整个悲伤的曲目， 如果你
grow up in a culture that has no concept
在 没有概念 的文化中成长
for sadness you don't experience sadness
因为悲伤， 你不会 经历悲伤
and you don't perceive sadness because
你不会感到悲伤，因为
your brain becomes wired to make
你的大脑变得有线
whatever mental events that are exist in
无论存在什么心理事件
your particular culture so for
你的特殊文化
artificial intelligence systems the idea
人工智能系统的想法
of emotional intelligence is really
情商真的是
difficult and it seems like it's an
困难，似乎是一个
important thing to try to instill so for
尝试灌输这样的重要事情
human beings where do you see the
人类你在哪里看到的
importance on the priority list of what
重要的是什么的优先级列表
makes us human where does emotion sit I
让我们成为人类情感在哪里
usually think that's the wrong question
通常认为这是错误的问题
to ask because no I mean I think I think
问 ，因为没有我的意思是，我认为，我 认为
people constantly ask that question but
人们经常问这个问题但是
I don't think it's the right question to
我不认为 这是正确的 问题
ask because you know some cultures in
问，因为你知道 在 某些文化
our on our planet don't even have a
我们这个星球甚至都没有
concept for emotion and people don't
情感和人的概念没有
while they experience what I'm going to
当他们体验 我要去的时候
refer to as in scientific terms we call
我们称之为科学术语
effect which is our simple feelings of
效果这是我们简单的感受
feeling pleasant or unpleasant or
感到愉快 或不愉快或
feeling worked up or calm or comfortable
感觉努力，平静或舒适
or discs or you know having discomfort
或 光盘或你知道有 不适
these are feelings that come directly
这些是 直接 感受到的
from the internal state of the physical
从物理 的内部状态
systems in your body not everybody makes
你体内的系统并不是每个人都能做到的
emotions out of those feelings and in
那种 感情和情感
fact we often don't make emotions out of
其实我们经常不作情绪出来 的
this way so those feelings the way to
这样那些感受的 方式就是这样
think about it is that your brain comes
想想 你的大脑来了
wired to regulate your body actually
有线实际调节你的身体
sort of take that back you your brain
把你 的大脑 带回来
comes wired when you're born your brain
当你出生在你的大脑时，它会被连线
comes wired with the potential to
与潜力有关
regulate your body infants actually
实际上调节你的身体婴儿
don't regulate their own nervous systems
不要调节自己的神经系统
very well they can't put themselves to
很好，他们不能把自己
sleep they can't calm themselves down
睡觉他们无法平静下来
they can't regulate their own
他们无法规范 自己
temperature that's what they need
温度就是他们所需要的
caregivers for and as caregivers
护理人员和护理人员
regulate the nervous systems of their
调节他们的神经系统
infants that wires the infant's brain
连接婴儿大脑的婴儿
right so infant little infant brains
对，所以婴儿小婴儿的大脑
aren't born like little miniature adult
并不像小小的成年人那样天生
brains they're born at waiting for a set
他们出生在等待一套的大脑
of wiring instructions from the world
来自世界各地的接线说明
and they wire themselves to the physical
他们把自己连接到物理上
and social
和社交
realities that they grow in and as they
他们 成长的现实和他们
learn to do this they experience these
学会这样做， 他们体验 这些
simple feelings that you know a feeling
简单的感觉，你知道一种感觉
Pleasant or unpleasant feeling worked up
愉快或不愉快的感觉起作用
or feeling calm these are kind of like
或者感到平静这些都有点 像
barometer readings in a way they're very
气压计读数的方式非常好
simple and they lack a lot of detail
很简单，他们缺乏很多 细节
because of how we're wired and we have
因为我们 有线 和我们有
to make sense of them and the way that a
理解他们和a的方式
culture makes sense of them is not
文化使他们感觉不是
always about emotion so I would say you
永远关于情感所以我会说你
know in our culture when we lose
当我们失败时，在我们的文化中知道
something significant like a loved one
像爱人一样重要的东西
we feel sad into heat intuition people
我们对 热直觉的人 感到难过
feel sick they they have an illness it's
他们生病了， 他们有病 了
not sadness a hundred or two hundred
别难过一两百
years ago there was an emotion called
几年前 有一种叫做的情感
nostalgia which killed people was
杀人的怀旧之情
thought to kill people after you know
你知道之后会想杀人
for example after serving in World War
例如在世界大战中服役之后
one we would now call that depression
我们现在 称之为 抑郁症
it's not just a matter of changing the
这不仅仅是改变问题的问题
label of something it's actually the
事物的标签实际上是
formation of the experience is very
形成的经验非常
different so if you want to build an
不同 所以，如果你想建立一个
intelligent agent
智能代理
I don't think emotion is what you need
我认为情感不是你所需要的
to endow it with you need to endow it
赋予它你需要赋予它
with these basic ingredients that it can
有了这些基本成分，它可以
use to make whatever experiences or
用来做任何 经历或
guide whatever actions make whatever
指导无论采取什么行动
States or guide whatever actions are
国家或 指导任何行动
relevant to the situations that it's in
与它所处的情况有关
that will be different if it's an
如果它是一个将是不同的
American or a British or a Western
美国人，英国人或西方人
urbanized environment than say if you
城市化的环境 比你说的要好
were to go to Tanzania and steady
我们要稳稳地前往坦桑尼亚
you know the HUD's ax who are hunting
你知道正在狩猎的HUD的 斧头
and gathering since that culture since
从那以后收集了那种文化
the Pleistocene so do you have words or
更新世所以你有话语或者
human interpretable labels on these
这些人类可解释的标签
basic ingredients that we can understand
我们可以理解的基本成分
so I mean I think the first thing to
所以我的意思是我认为第一件事
understand is that when we think about
理解的是，当我们 思考时
building an intelligent agent we think
建立我们认为的智能代理
about endowing the agent with cognition
关于赋予代理人认知
or with emotion or with the ability to
或有情感或有能力
COO you
首席运营官你
to perceive things in the world because
感知世界上的事物， 因为
as humans that those are these are the
作为人类，那些是这些
things that are really important to us
事情是对我们真的很重要
especially in our culture thinking
特别是在我们的文化思想中
feeling seeing and other cultures you
感觉看与其他文化的 你
know they have different ways of parsing
知道 他们有不同的 解析方式
things but the truth is that your brain
事情但事实 是 你的大脑
did not evolve so that you could think
没有进化，所以你可以思考
and feel and see it evolved brains
感觉并看到它进化出来的大脑
evolved to control bodies brains evolved
进化到控制身体进化的大脑
so that they could control the various
这样他们就能控制各种各样的东西
systems of the body as creatures move
身体系统作为生物 移动
around in order to gain resources like
为了 获得 像这样的资源
food and water and a brain has to figure
食物和水以及大脑必须要有数字
out how much resources to expend on
出 多少 资源耗费上
getting additional resources now that
现在获得额外的资源
may sound really trivial but it turns
可能听起来真的微不足道，但它转变
out it's actually really hard and
出它实际上真的很难 和
scientists actually haven't really
科学家其实并没有真的
figured out completely how brains do
彻底弄清楚大脑是怎么做的
this I mean what's really interesting to
这意味着真正 有趣的 是什么
me is that if you look for example at
如果你在寻找 例子， 那就是 我
computer vision try to figure out you
计算机视觉试图找出 你
know how how to make an agent see that's
懂得 如何使代理人看到这
a pretty much solved problem not
一个几乎解决不了的问题
completely it's a pretty much solved
完全它已经解决了
problem the basics are solved it's your
问题基础解决了它是你的
perception problems yeah the peer
感知 问题是 同行
perception problem however if you want
但是 ，如果你想感受问题
to create an agent that just reaches out
创建一个刚刚伸出的代理
smoothly grabs a glass and brings it
顺利抓起一杯并带来它
into the body to drink that problem is
进入体内喝那个问题就是
not solved something is simple as
没有解决的东西 也很简单
movement which we think of as this
我们认为是这样的运动
really basic thing like oh it's so
真的很基本的事情哦，就是这样
trivial all animals can do it is
所有动物都可以做到这一点
actually the heart at one of the hardest
实际上是最难的一个人的心脏
problems to solve and the brains
要解决的问题 和大脑
basically I mean there's a whole story
基本上我的意思是有一个完整的故事
here about evolution which has nothing
这里关于没有任何东西的进化
to do with having a lizard brain which
与 蜥蜴大脑有关
is wrapped in you know a cognitive brain
你知道一个认知大脑
or anything like that that's a reference
或类似的东西， 这是一个参考
to the Trion brain which a lot of people
去 了很多 人 的Trion 脑
believe it's a way of thinking about
相信这是 思考 的 一种方式
brain evolution instead what we what
大脑进化而不是我们的东西
seems to be the case is that as bodies
似乎就是 这样的机构
got larger
变大了
and there were more systems because the
还有更多的系统，因为
nish of the animal the environment the
动物的环境是什么
animal got bigger and bigger and bigger
动物变得越来越大 ，更大
brains also had to get bigger but they
大脑也必须变得更大，但他们
had to get bigger to a point with some
必须得到更大的与一些点
constraints like they have to be you
像他们必须是你的约束
have to keep metabolic costs down it's
必须保持新陈代谢 成本
really important if you don't you know
如果你不知道，真的很重要
creatures get sick and die and we can
生物生病死亡 ，我们可以
talk about what that means in terms of
谈什么 来讲意味着
depression or metabolic illnesses or
抑郁症或代谢性疾病或
what-have-you but so what are the basic
什么是你，但那么什么是基本的
ingredients well one of the basic
成分 很好基本之一
ingredients is that your brain is
成分是你的大脑
controlling your body all the time
控制你的身体所有 的时间
whether you feel it or not whether
不管你是否有这种感觉
you're thinking about it or not whether
你在考虑是否
you're asleep or awake certain parts of
你睡着了或醒了某些部分
your brain are always very active all
你的大脑总是很活跃
the time even when you're sleeping or
甚至当你在睡觉或时间
else you'd be dead and those parts of
否则你会死了，那些部分
the brain that are controlling your
正在 控制你的 大脑
heart and your lungs and your immune
心脏和你的肺部和你的免疫力
system and all of those regions that are
系统和所有这些区域
controlling the systems of your body are
控制你身体的系统
also helping your brain to represent the
也帮助你的大脑代表
sensory consequences of those changes in
这些变化的感官后果
your body which you don't feel directly
你不直接感觉到的 身体
you don't feel your heart beating most
你不会感到心脏跳动最多
of the time you don't feel your lungs
的时候，你不 觉得你的肺
expanding most of the time and there's a
大部分时间都在扩展而且有一个
really good reason why we are all wired
我们 都有 线的 原因 真的很好
not to feel those things and that is
不要觉得那些 东西， 那 就是
you'd never pay attention to anything
你永远不会注意任何事情
outside in the world ever again if you
如果你 在 世界 之外的 话
could feel every little movement that
能够感受每 一点动静 即
was going on inside your body so your
在 你的身体 内部 进行 ， 所以你的身体
brain represents those as a summary
大脑代表那些作为总结
these kind of simple summary feelings
这些简单的总结感受
you feel good you feel bad you feel
你感觉良好 ，你 心疼你 的感觉
great
大
you feel like you feel really
你觉得你觉得真的很糟糕
jittery you feel really calm and these
你觉得 这些 感到非常 冷静
feelings are not emotions they sometimes
感情不是他们有时候的情绪
get your brain can make them into
让你的大脑可以 让他们进入
emotions but they're with you every
情绪，但他们每个人都和你在一起
waking moment of your life there are
唤醒你的生活时刻有
properties
性能
consciousness in the way that lightness
意识在轻盈的方式
and darkness is a property of vision and
黑暗是视觉和视觉的属性
sometimes we make them into emotions
有时我们会把它们 变成情绪
when they're vit when we have a big
当我们有一个大的时候他们是 维生素的
change in our heart rate or a big change
改变我们的心率或发生重大变化
in our in our breathing rate or a big
在我们的呼吸率或大
change in our temperature or a big surge
我们的温度变化或大幅增加
of glucose we might the brain might make
大脑可能会产生葡萄糖
a motion out of those changes those very
那些动作就是那些改变了
strong changes which you will feel as
强烈的变化，这你会觉得
really feeling unpleasant or really
真的感觉不愉快或真的
feeling Pleasant but your brain might
感觉愉快，但你的大脑可能
also make hunger or your brain might
也可以使饥饿或你的大脑变得可能
make an instance of a physical sensation
做一个身体感觉的例子
like nausea or your brain might even
像恶心 或你的大脑甚至可能
make a perception of the world like
让世界的感知像
that's a nice guy that guy is an asshole
那个家伙是个混蛋 ，真是个好人
this is a really delicious drink that's
这是一个非常美味的饮料 ，是
a beautiful painting those are also
那些也是美丽的画
moments where these simple feelings
这些简单感受的时刻
which we call effect are very strong so
我们称之为效果非常强烈
effect is a basic ingredient there are
效果是一个基本的成分有
others that I could talk about too it's
其他我也可以谈论它的
not the only one but one of the things I
不是唯一的，而是我的一件事
think that that sometimes people who are
认为有时候那些人
studying to build AI systems don't
学习构建AI系统不会
realize is that the brain its
意识到大脑就是它
fundamental job is to keep your body
基本工作是保持身体健康
alive and well and if you don't have
如果你没有 ，那就活得很好
some kind of body to regulate with
某种身体与规范
effective feelings that come from that
来自那的有效感受
regulation or something like that it's
法规或类似的东西，它是
you're kind of gonna be out of luck I
你有点 不幸我
think in rendering something that looks
想一想看起来像什么
more something that seems more human
更多看似更人性化的东西
right so maybe you can elaborate like in
对，所以也许你可以详细说明
the book sapiens that we as human beings
这本书使 我们成为人类
are really good on mass as a thousands
成千上万的 人 真的很好
millions of people together believing
数百万人在一起相信
something even if it's not true so
即使不是这样的事情也是如此
while scientifically sort of from a
虽然科学地从一个
neuroscience perspective it may be very
神经科学的观点可能非常
true that emotions aren't real I didn't
确实情绪不是真实的我没有
think real but I said they're not there
认为真实，但我说他们不在那里
there isn't so interesting you finished
你完成的并不是那么有趣
yeah yeah so what I'm trying to say is
是的，所以我想说的是
also from AI perspective is they become
从AI的角度来看，他们也成了
these trivial ideas of mapping a smile
这些琐碎的想法映射出一个微笑
to being happy and these kind of trivial
幸福和这些微不足道的
ideas become real to us through
通过 思想真正成为我们
Hollywood through cultural spreading of
好莱坞通过文化传播
information and we start to believe this
信息，我们开始相信这一点
and therefore it becomes real
因此 ， 它 变成了现实
innocent in in in as much as anything is
无辜在尽可能什么是
real about our cult our perception
关于我们崇拜的真实感受
together so it's really important
这是非常重要的
scientifically the ideas that you're
科学地说出 你 的想法
presenting but does that mean there's
呈现但这是否意味着有
just because our brain doesn't feel
只因为我们的大脑 感觉不到
those explicit emotions does I mean
我的意思是那些明确的情绪
they're not real I didn't say we don't
他们不是真的我没说我们没有
feel explicit emotions so I want to be
感受到明确的情绪所以我想 成为
really clear about this because it's an
真的很清楚这是因为 它是一个
interesting this you know this sum this
有趣的是， 你知道这 一点
inference it's an interesting inference
推断这是一个有趣的推论
that people often make and so but it's
人们经常这样做但是这样
it's a mistake and it's a mistake that
这是一个错误，这是一个错误
betrays a certain kind of thinking that
背叛了某种这种思维
we do in this culture and is it's the
我们在这种文化中做的就是这样
mistake of the following sort so when I
以下那种错误， 所以当我
say there is no facial expression that
说没有 面部 表情
is diagnostic of a single emotion that
是对单一情绪的诊断
doesn't mean that people don't express
并不意味着人们不表达
emotion they certainly do express
他们肯定表达的情感
emotion they just don't you know when
情感，他们只是你不知道什么时候
when they're in a state of anger in a
当他们处于愤怒状态时
state of sadness or in a state of awe
悲伤 的状态或 敬畏 的状态
their faces don't do one thing when I
当我的时候，他们的脸不做一件事
say well your body can do many things
说好你的身体可以做很多事情
when you're angry or when you're sad or
当你生气或当 你感到悲伤或
but let's take anger your heart rate can
但是，让我们的心率加快
go up it can go down it can stay the
上去它可以下去它可以留下来
same your breathing rate can go up it
同样你的呼吸率可以上升
can go down it can stay the same the
可以下去它可以保持不变
same pattern that you see in anger you
你在愤怒中看到的相同模式
sometimes see in sadness and you
有时看到悲伤和你
sometimes see in fear you sometimes even
有时甚至会害怕 你
see it in enthusiasm and in awe so does
以热情和敬畏的态度看待它
that mean that emotions aren't real no
这意味着情绪不是真的没有
emotions are real but but sometimes
情绪是真实的，但有时候
things are real because the physical
事物是真实的，因为物理
meaning of
的意义
the signal is endowed in the signal okay
信号被赋予信号好了
so when your retina communicates to your
所以当你的视网膜传达给你的
brain that you have that you are faced
你所面对的大脑
with a wavelength of that you know is
用你知道的波长
600 you know 600 nanometers the signal
600你知道600纳米的信号
is endowed in your brain that's like in
被赋予你的大脑，就像在
the signal it's not like interpret you
这个信号不像解释你
don't interpret that it's 600 you know
不要解释它是600你知道的
nanometers it is 600 nanometers the
纳米是600纳米
informations in the signal but when you
信号中的信息但是当你
see read that information is not in the
看到阅读这些 信息是不是在
signal your brain has added information
表示你的大脑已经添加了 信息
that isn't in the signal itself in a
这是不是在信号本身 的
sense your brain has imposed meaning on
感觉你的大脑强加了意义
a signal that the signal doesn't have on
信号没有的信号
its own they'll let me back up and give
它自己会让我支持 并给予
a different example to make it a little
一个不同的例子让它变得 有点
easier and then will reproach this
更容易，然后 将责备这一点
there's a there are some things that we
我们有一些 东西
impose this is true almost of all
几乎 所有人都 强加于此
civilization right that we there are
我们有正确的文明
some things that are real by virtue of
一些真实的东西
the fact that we agree that they exist
我们同意 它们存在 的事实
little pieces of paper serve as money or
小纸片作为钱或
now you know bitcoin or little pieces of
现在你知道 比特币或 小件了
plastic or gold or diamonds or in the
塑料或金或钻石 或在
past barley
过去的大麦
salt shells rocks serve as currency have
盐壳 岩石 作为货币有
value only because a group of people
价值只因为一群人
agree that they have value so we impose
同意他们有价值，所以我们强加
meaning on objects and once we all agree
一旦我们 都同意，对物体的意义
that that object actually has value we
那个对象 实际上 有价值我们
can trade it for material goods the
你对换材料商品
minute that some of us disagree that we
我们有些人 不同意我们的一分钟
risk we withdraw our consent right the
风险我们撤回我们的同意 权利
things lose their value that's what
事情失去其价值，这就是
happened in the mortgage crisis that's
发生在抵押贷款危机中
what happened in the tulip crisis in the
在郁金香危机中发生了什么
you know the Netherlands in the 17th
你知道 17日 的荷兰
century or 16th century when it was
世纪或16世纪的 时候
money currency
货币
this because we impose meaning on
这是因为我们强加了意义
objects in the world physical objects in
世界物体中的 物体
the world that themselves don't have
他们自己没有 的世界
that meaning on their own and they are
这意味着他们自己而且他们是
very real money is very real to people I
非常真实的钱对 我 来说非常真实
can stick somebody's head in a brain
可以将某人的脑袋贴在大脑中
scanner and show you that they
扫描仪并告诉你他们
experience value in a very real way but
以非常真实的方式体验价值但是
that that reality is constructed by the
那个现实是 由...构建的
fact that they have learned the value in
事实上， 他们已经学会了 价值
a particular culture well that's also
一个特定的文化 也是如此
what we do with emotion we impose
我们用情感做了什么
meaning on certain physical signals that
对某些物理信号的意义
they don't have by on their own and but
他们没有对自己 和但拥有
we have collective intentionality we all
我们都有集体意向
agree that scowling is sometimes anger
同意皱眉有时是愤怒
and so it becomes anger in a very real
所以它变得非常真实
way just like little pieces of paper
就像小纸片一样
become money so it sounds like you kind
变成金钱所以听起来 像你善良
of think about the expression R emotions
考虑表达R情绪
a kind of language as an extension of a
一种语言作为 一个 扩展
language that will learn in the same way
将以 同样的 方式 学习的语言
that we collectively agree in a language
我们在一种语言中集体同意
ana lexicon and how we use that language
ana lexicon以及我们如何使用该语言
sure you could think of it that way I
确保你能想到 这样的 说法我
mean everything everything in our
意味着一切的一切我们
culture is almost everything
文化几乎应有尽有
agriculture is a function of social
农业是社会的功能
reality in this way we are citizens of a
以这种方式现实，我们是一个公民
country because we all agree that the
国家，因为我们都同意 ，
country exists more or less and wow you
国家 或多或少地 存在 并且哇哇
guys barely even laughed at that okay
伙计们甚至 嘲笑那个 没关系
[Music]
[音乐]
what's a revolution a revolution is when
什么是革命，什么是革命
some people in the country withdraw
这个国家的 一些人 退出了
their consent they no longer agree right
他们同意他们不再 同意正确
a president has powers in a country
总统在一个国家拥有权力
because we all agree that a president
因为我们都同意 总统
has powers present only as powers by
有权力仅作为权力出现
virtue the fact that we all agree that
凭借着事实是 ，我们都同意 ，
he or she has powers if we stop agreeing
如果我们停止同意， 他或 她就有权力
the president doesn't have those powers
总统没有这些 权力
anymore it's very real people's lives
这是非常真实的人的生活
depend outcomes of real people depend on
取决于真实的人的结果取决于
these social realities that we build and
我们建立的这些社会现实
nurture and we why are these social
培养，我们为什么这些社会
realities into the brains of our
进入我们大脑的现实
children as we socialize them and when
孩子们，因为我们将他们和他们社交
people move from one culture to another
人们从一种文化转向另一种文化
they have to learn the new social
他们必须 学习新的社会
reality that they are faced with and if
他们面临的现实和如果
they don't they get very sick physically
他们不会在身体上生病
because our ability to agree on what
因为我们有能力 就什么达成一致
something means actually is important
事实上意味着重要
for regulating our nervous systems so
为了调节我们的神经 系统
can you speak to that a little bit I
你能跟 我 谈谈吗？
mean for machine learning methods for
机器学习方法的 意思
systems that learn to behave based on a
学会基于a行为的系统
certain reward it's important to kind of
某种奖励对某种方式很重要
have some ground truth and and learn so
有一些基本的事实，并且学习 如此
how do it sounds like the expression of
它是如何听起来像的表达
emotion is learned can you talk about
你能谈到的是情感学习吗？
how we learn to fit into our culture by
我们如何通过学习融入我们的 文化
expressing emotion with our phase body
用我们的 相体 表达情感
given the context given the rich what's
鉴于丰富的 内容给予了 什么
that process look like when does it
那个过程看起来就像什么时候一样
happen
发生
how much sure well you know I mean yeah
多么肯定你知道我的意思是的
I wrote a 400 page book so I'll try to
我写了400页 的书，所以我会尽力
do it in like a couple sentences yeah so
做到这一点像 一两句呀等等
so how does it how does an infant learn
那么婴儿 如何 学习呢？
anything so an infant's born and it
任何婴儿出生的事情都是如此
can't
不能
do anything for itself it can't regulate
为自己做任何事都无法调节
its own nervous system it can't keep its
它自己的神经系统无法保持它
body systems balanced this is a term
身体系统平衡这是一个术语
scientific term for this is alice stasis
对此的 科学术语 是爱丽丝停滞
alice stasis is your brain's ability to
爱丽丝瘀血是你大脑的能力
predict what your body is going to need
预测你的身体会 需要
before it needs it and tries to meet
在它需要之前并试图 满足
those needs before they arise so an
这些需求在它们出现之前就 这样了
example would be if you're gonna stand
例如， 如果你要站起来的话
up if your brain is gonna stand you up
如果你的大脑会让你站起来
it has to raise your blood pressure
它具有提高你的 血压
before it stands you up if it doesn't
如果它没有 ， 它会让你站起来
you'll fall that's costly from metabolic
你会因为新陈代谢而付出代价
standpoint it's costly you'll hurt
从某种角度来看，你会受到伤害
yourself so an infant's brain can't do
你自己这么婴儿的大脑是做不到的
this very well an infant doesn't know
这很好 的婴儿不知道
when to go to sleep and when to wake up
何时入睡 以及何时醒来
an infant doesn't can't feed itself
婴儿不能自食其力
can't regulate its own temperature
不能调节自己的温度
someone else has to do it and when
别人必须这样做 ，何时
someone does it the infant is learning
有人这样做，婴儿 正在学习
the infant is learning it's taking in
婴儿正在学习 它正在接受
sights and sounds and smells and the
景点和声音， 气味和气味
physical sensations from the body which
来自身体的身体感觉
are comfortable and pleasant when the
舒适愉快的时候
infant Alice stasis is maintained so
婴儿爱丽丝瘀滞维持 如此
right from the get-go an infant is
从 一开始 就是 一个婴儿
learning statistical learning you know
学习你知道的统计学习
the capturing events including their
捕获事件包括他们的
consequence for the infant's body
婴儿身体的后果
some people think babies are born you
有些人认为婴儿是 你 出生的
know attached already to their
知道已经附在他们身上了
caregivers but they're not actually
照顾者， 但他们实际上并非如此
infants don't even know what a caregiver
婴儿甚至不知道什么是看护人
is it's just that the caregiver is there
只是护理人员在 那里
constantly meeting that infant's needs
不断满足婴儿的需求
that's how infants start to learn now if
这就是婴儿现在开始学习的方式
there are statistical regularities like
有统计规律，如
for example an infant is not born with
例如，婴儿不是天生的
the ability to recognize a face as a
识别脸部的 能力
face but it learns that in like the
面对， 但它学会了像
first couple of days of life why because
生命的前几天 为什么呢？
human faces have some statistical
人脸 有一些统计
regularities to them right to eyes and
他们对 眼睛和眼睛的规律性
nose and a mouth kind of in the same
鼻子和嘴巴 一样
place most of the time so it learns
大部分时间放置所以它学习
really quickly but here's the
真的很快， 但这里是
interesting thing around three months of
三个月 左右 有趣的 事情
age infants start to learn
年龄婴儿 开始学习
what we call abstract categories they
我们所说的抽象的范畴，他们
start to learn that some things which
开始学习一些事情
don't look the same or sound the same or
看起来 不一样或听起来不一样
smell the same actually have the same
闻起来一样实际上也一样
function and how do they learn this they
功能以及他们如何了解这一点
learn it with words so if you do an
如果你做的话，用文字学习它
experiment with a three month old three
试验一个 三个月大的三岁
months old okay and you say to that baby
个月大的 好，你给 宝宝 说
very very intentionally look sweetie
非常非常故意看起来亲爱的
this is a one and you put the web down
这是一个，你把网络下来
and it makes a noise like a beep and
它会发出哔哔声和嗡嗡声
then you say I'm like I don't have props
然后你说我喜欢我没有道具
and then you see my wallet yeah okay and
然后你 看到 我的 钱包 好了
then you say give me your wallet yeah
然后你说给我 你的钱包是的
give me your wallet and then you say
把你的钱包给我 ，然后 你说
look sweetie
看起来亲爱的
this is a WoG and you put the wog down
这是一个WoG你放下了wog
and it makes a beep if you say look
如果你说看起来会发出哔哔声
sweetie
糖果
this is a WoG that infant expects that
这是婴儿期望的WoG
object to beep why is that important
对象发出蜂鸣声为什么这么重要
because in the real experiments this
因为在真实的实验中
might be yellow and squishy and tall and
可能是黄色的，柔软的，高大的
this might be red and pointy and you
这可能是红色和尖尖的你
know hard and this might be you know so
很难知道，这可能是你 知道的
lots of different perceptual features
许多不同的感知功能
but but the infant nose learns that the
但婴儿的鼻子却 知道了
word is inviting the infant to
这个词是邀请婴儿来的
understand that the function of those
了解那些功能
very different physical signals are
非常不同的物理 信号
actually the same similarly you can take
实际上你可以采取同样的方式
you know six objects that are exactly
你知道六个确切的对象
identical in their physical features how
如何相同的物理特征
they sound how they smell what they feel
他们听起来如何闻到他们的感受
like what they look like and you can
喜欢他们的样子，你 可以
name three of them with one word and
用一个单词命名其中三个
three of them with the other word and
其中三个用另一个词和
the infant will understand that these
婴儿会明白这些
are actually different objects that
实际上是不同的对象
happens a little after you know not not
在你知道不是之后发生了一点
as early as three months
早在 三个月
but the point is that when we talk all
但重点是，当我们谈论所有
the time we use words all the time what
当时我们使用的话所有的时间什么
do we do with infants we're constantly
我们是否经常与婴儿一起做
pointing things out and labeling them
指着东西出来和 他们 贴标签
this is a dog this is a cat you're angry
这是一只狗，这是 一只 你生气 的猫
this person's sad Oh mummys really happy
这个人的伤心 哦妈妈真的很开心
today oh you know mommy loves you
今天哦，你知道妈妈 爱你
Oh daddy's really excited about this and
哦， 爸爸对此非常兴奋
so on and so forth and infants learn
等等，婴儿学习
really really quickly words are
真的很快就会说出来的话
considered to be kind of invitations to
被认为是一种 邀请
form abstract concepts that is the basis
形成抽象概念，这是基础
of almost all of the you know mental
几乎所有你都知道的精神
categories that we that that we mental
我们心理上的 那些类别
events that we experience we're
我们遇到的事件
basically teaching children to form
基本上教孩子形成
these abstract categories not and that's
这些抽象类别不是，那就是
the basis of money and it's the basis of
金钱的基础和它的基础
rules that we have with each other and
我们彼此 之间的规则
what we expect from each other it's the
我们从 彼此 期待 它的
basis of a lot of the sort of functional
许多功能的基础
categories that we use in everyday life
我们在日常生活 中使用的类别
we're impose meaning on sensory on
我们实行的感官 上 的意义
sensory arrays that those sensory arrays
感官阵列， 这些阵列的感官
in and of themselves don't necessarily
本身并不一定
have they only have that meaning because
他们只有 那个意思，因为
you and I both learn that that package
你和我都知道那个包裹
of sensory array means something so when
感觉阵列意味着什么时候
I make that you can anticipate what will
我说你可以预料到会发生什么
happen next just because we've learned
接下来只是因为我们已经学会了
those are they're wired into our brains
那些是他们被连接到我们的大脑
you know in our culture and when we go
你知道我们的文化 和我们去的时候
to a different culture we have to learn
不同的文化我们 要学习
sometimes different packages yeah
有时不同的包是啊
different mappings so you're saying that
不同的映射所以你这么 说
there's a few sources of sensory data
有一些感官数据来源
and a few building blocks inside us the
我们里面有几块积木
feelings of some kind that we learn to
某种感情，我们学会
then from an early that we've come born
然后从早期我们出生
with those or part of what your brain is
与那些或部分你的大脑是什么
doing is it's trying to make sense of
这是在 尝试理解
the sensory array around it so from your
它周围的感官阵列也是 如此
brains purse so from your brains
从你的大脑大脑钱包
perspective just think about from your
从你的角度思考
brains perspective your brains
大脑透视你的大脑
perspective it spends its entire life
它花了整个生命
trapped in a dark silent box
被困在一个黑暗的无声盒子里
[Music]
[音乐]
Anna NASA makes sense of what's going on
安娜 美国宇航局了解 正在 发生的 事情
around in the world so that knows what
在世界各地， 所以知道什么
to do to keep itself alive right and
做的，让自己活着的 权利 ，
well but it has to it has to know what
好吧，但它必须要知道什么
to do based on it has to know what
要做的基础就是要知道什么
what's happening all around it only from
它周围 发生 了 什么
the effects that it receives through the
它通过的收到的影响
sensory systems of the body so a flash
身体的感觉系统如此闪光
of light
光
what's a flash of light it could be
什么是闪光可能是什么
anything what you know what's a look
什么你知道什么是外观
like a siren a siren could be you know a
就像 一个警报器，警报器 可能是你知道的
firetruck or it could be somebody's car
救火车 或它可能是某人的车
alarm went off or it could be a doorbell
警报响了，也可能是门铃
or it could be right any particular
或者它可能是正确的
sensory cue could have multiple causes
感觉提示可能有多种原因
so your brains trapped basically in your
所以你的大脑基本上困在 你的 脑袋里
skull and all it gets are the effects
头骨和所有它得到的是效果
the sensory effects of stuff that
东西的感官效果
happens in the world but it has to
发生在 世界 ，但它有
figure out what those things are so that
找出 那些东西是什么
it knows what to do so how does it do
它知道该怎么做， 它是 如何 做的
that well it has something else that it
这也 有 别的东西，它
can draw on it has your past experiences
可以借鉴它有你过去的经验
your brain basically is doesn't store
你的大脑基本上是不存储的
experiences from the past it can
过去的经历可以
reconstitute them in its wiring and
重建他们的布线和
that's what it uses to guess at what
这就是它用来猜测什么的东西
those sensory cues me of those sensory
这些感官提示我的感官
changes me so in one situation a siren
改变 我，所以在一种情况下 警笛
means one thing in another situation it
在另一种情况下它意味着一件事
means another a flash of light means one
意思是另一个闪光意味着一个
thing in one situation and a different
在一种 情况和不同的事情
thing in another so your brain is using
在另一个东西， 所以你的大脑 正在使用
past experience to make guesses about
过去的猜测经验
what these sensory changes me and so
这 是什么 感觉改变了我等
that it knows what to do and it has the
它知道该怎么 做而且它 有
same relationship to the sensory changes
在感官上的变化同样的关系
in your body
在你的身体里
what's an ache in your stomach well it
你胃里有什么疼痛呢
could be hunger it could be anger it
可能是饥饿，这可能是愤怒 吧
could be discussed it could be longing
可以讨论它可能是渴望
it could be nausea it's not that there's
可能是恶心，不是那样的
one ache in your stomach for nausea and
胃部疼痛，恶心 和 疼痛
another ache in your stomach for hunger
你肚子里的另一个疼痛是 饥饿
there are many
有许多
aches in your stomach any different
你 肚子里的 疼痛有 什么不同
feelings of achiness for nausea and many
恶心和恶心的感觉
different feelings of aching is for
不同的疼痛感是为了
hunger and sometimes they overlap so
饥饿，有时他们重叠
your brain has to make the same kinds of
你的大脑必须做同样的事情
guesses about what's going on in your
猜测你的生活中发生了什么
body as it does about what the sensory
身体， 因为它关于什么感官
events mean in the world and that's
事件意味着世界和那个
really what it's doing it's it's
真的是它正在做的事情就是 这样
guessing and making sense of the sensory
猜测和理解感官
array so that it knows what to do next
数组， 以便 它知道下一步 该做什么
and when it guesses wrong it takes in
当它猜错时它会接受
that the you know the the sort of
你 知道的那种
information that it didn't predict well
信息 ，它没有很好预测
which you know in psychology we have a
你 在心理学上知道我们有一个
really fancy name for that we call it
为此， 我们把它叫做真正看中的名字
learning your brain takes in the
学习你的大脑需要了解
information that it didn't predict and
信息， 它没有预测 和
so that it can predict better than the
这样它可以比预测更好
next time to make sense of things the
下次要 弄清楚事情了
next time so you kind of answered this a
下一次让你有种回答 这个
little bit I'd like to elaborate on it
我想详细说明一下
if you were to build a robot that
如果你要建立一个机器人
performs maybe passes the Turing test or
执行可能通过图灵测试或
performs at the low bar level of instead
而是 在低杠杆 水平执行
of myself here today it would be a robot
我 今天在这里会 是一个机器人
talking to you it'd be convincing as a
和 你 说话 它会 令人信服
human how would you what kind of how
人类你怎么样怎么样
would you build that system in a sense
你会在某种意义上 建立 这个系统 吗？
in paralleling the infant's what
与婴儿并列的是什么
essential aspect of the infant
婴儿的重要方面
experience do you think is important it
经验你认为重要吗？
needs to well I mean I you know I don't
需要很好我的意思是我知道我没有
I'm not a computer scientist so but so
我不是计算机科学家 ，所以
the way that I would say it is it needs
我 想说它需要的方式
to have a body
有一个身体
these have something like physical
这些都有类似物理的东西
systems or an analogy to physical
系统或物理的类比
systems it has to do something analogous
系统必须做类似的事情
to a low stasis so whatwhat's sorry to
对于低位停滞，所以有点遗憾
elaborate so what would be the goal for
详细说明那将 是 什么 目标
the system you kind of mentioned
你提到的系统
previously that the goal will be to for
以前的目标是 为了
the brain to just stabilize itself no
大脑只是稳定自己没有
it's not that the brain is stabilized
并不是 说大脑是 稳定的
though you know so people talk about
虽然你知道这样的人谈
reward what is reward and machine
奖励什么是奖励和机器
learning is pretty easy it's it's
学习 很容易就是它
something but
但是
it's it's mathematical so it's there's
它是数学的所以它就是这样的
no philosophy to it you just
没有理念，它只是你
oh yeah there's philosophy to everything
哦是的，一切都是哲学
right whether you admit it or not as a
无论你承认与否
different story right yeah so you wanted
不同的故事是的所以你想要的
to play a game of chess playing give
下棋玩得到 游戏
them go you wanted to pick up a water
他们去你想要取水
bottle is uh okay but what is reward
瓶子好吧，但奖励 是 什么
existence dopamine is actually not
存在多巴胺实际上不是
reward dopamine is effort dopamine is
奖励多巴胺是多巴胺的努力
necessary for effort it's not necessary
努力是必要的， 没有必要
for reward
为了奖励
maybe it's commonly if you read the most
也许这通常是你阅读最多的
caught those up to date literature that
抓住那些最新的文献
is what you'll see that it's actually
是你会看到它实际上是什么
people can animals can find things
人们可以动物找到东西
rewarding can be without without
奖励可以没有
dopamine actually but they they they
实际上是多巴胺，但他们是他们
need to open to move they need dopamine
需要打开移动他们需要多巴胺
to encode fits and to learn information
编码拟合和学习信息
so it's really for effort that is
所以它是真正的努力，是
required to work towards getting a
需要努力 获得一个
reward I would say and when the when a
奖励我会说， 什么时候一个
brain an animal brain a human any kind
大脑的动物脑人类 的任何一种
of animal brain miss predicts what the
动物脑小姐预测什么
reward will be that's what you see a
奖励将是你所看到的
real surge of dopamine because it the
真正的多巴胺激增， 因为它
animal has to adjust its action but
动物必须调整它的动作但是
reward is basically bringing the body
奖励基本上是带来身体的
back into a low stasis it feels good
回到低位停滞 感觉很好
when that happens and people will and
当这种情况发生时，人们会和
animals will work tremendously hard to
动物将非常努力地工作
have that happen so you know what is
有这样的事情，所以你知道是什么
motivation motivation is is expending
动机动机是消费
resources to get a reward so basically
基本上获得奖励的资源
if if you don't have something
如果你没有东西
like physical systems that have to be
这样的必须是物理系统
kept in balance water I mean for humans
保持平衡 水我的意思是人类
or for actually any living creature on
或实际上 任何生物
this planet even you know single-cell
这个星球甚至你 知道单细胞
organisms actually there's an analogy to
有机体实际上有一个类比
what we're talking about here to brains
我们在 这里谈论的是大脑
but you know salt water glucose all
但你知道所有的盐水葡萄糖
these systems have to be kept in balance
这些系统必须 保持平衡
and they have to be kept in balance in a
他们必须保持平衡
very very efficient way and that's the
非常非常有效的方式 ，这就是
motivating so-called motivating force
激励所谓的激励力量
really that's what that's what that's
真的就是这就是那个
what really brains are for so yeah and
真正的大脑是什么，是的，是的
that is the basis the consequence of
这是后果的基础
that regulation it are the basis of you
这条规则是你的基础
know effective feelings which are for
知道有效的感受
many many creatures on this planet a
这个星球上 有很多生物
property of consciousness ok so maybe if
意识的属性好吧 也许如果
it's ok we'll take some questions in the
它的确定，我们将采取 的 一些 问题
audience but first let me ask the last
观众， 但 首先让我问最后一个
question as so I'm building on the robot
因为 我正在建立 机器人的问题
question how would you build the same
问你如何建立相同的
kind of robot that you would be able to
一种机器人，你就可以
as a human being fall in love with well
作为一个人， 爱上了很好
you know people fall in love with their
你认识的人爱上自己
cars they fall in love with they fall in
他们坠入爱河的汽车
love with their blankets they fall in
他们 爱上 了他们的毯子
love with their toys you know you don't
爱 你 的玩具， 你知道你没有
need MIT doesn't need much to fall in
需要麻省理工学院不需要太多的东西
love with something the question is will
爱问题就是问题
it love you back
它爱你回来
I would elaborate I think I think yeah I
我会详细说明我想我是啊
think you're answering that love in the
以为 你是在 回答爱情
way we're defining it loosely in poetry
我们在诗歌中松散地定义它的方式
and culture as a social construct and
和 文化作为社会建构 和
its relative what I mean is sort of the
其相对 我的意思是什么样 的
idea of monogamous law a long-term love
一夫一妻制的想法是一种长期的 爱
that we have deep connection with other
我们与其他人有很深的联系
human beings that we have you're saying
我们有 你说的 人类
you could do the same with a car like a
你可以做同样的 像 汽车
nice 69 Mustang are you telling me that
漂亮69野马你告诉我 ，
you you telling me that you've never you
你告诉我 你从来没有
know anyone who's like so in love with
知道任何 喜欢这样爱的人
their car that you okay now here's the
他们的车，你现在好吗，这是
thing so one so here's the thing we we
所以 我们 就是 这样的事情
are social animals okay what does that
社交动物还可以
mean what does it mean to be a social
意思是什么 意思是一个社会
animal it means that we regulate each
动物， 这意味着我们规范每一个
other's nervous systems so our brain my
其他的神经系统，所以我们的大脑是我的
brain isn't just regulating my nervous
大脑不只是调节 我的紧张
system right now it's regulating yours
系统现在 它调节你的
and actually it's regulating other other
实际上它正在调节其他的
people's in the audience too and vice
人们在观众中也是如此
versa and why is that you know I mean
反之亦然，为什么 你知道我的意思
other animals do it too
其他动物也这样做
we're just looking really good at it but
我们只是看起来真的很擅长但是
other animals like there are some
其他动物就像 有一些
insects that are social species they
昆虫是 他们的 社会 物种
regulate each other's nervous systems
调节彼此的神经系统
they do it with chemicals they do it
他们用化学品来做这件事
with smell primarily and a little bit
气味主要和一点点
with touch like earwigs well you know
你知道，像触觉一样的触摸
like they can actually I have this great
就像他们实际上我可以拥有这个伟大的
picture of there's like totally
那张照片 完全 像
disgusting looking little bug but it's
看起来很恶心， 但它是
like you know cuddling it's a little
就像你知道拥抱它有点
baby ugly little ugly baby bug - it's
宝贝丑陋的小丑小宝贝虫 - 它的
adorable picture but you know what about
可爱的 图片，但你知道怎么样
mammals like rats well they also use
他们也使用像老鼠这样的哺乳动物
chemicals like smell but they also use
化学品如气味，但他们也使用
touch and to some extent they also use
触摸并在某种程度上他们也使用
sound these hearing primates add vision
声音这些听觉灵长类动物增加视力
and as primates we do all weaves all of
作为灵长类动物，我们所做的一切都是编织的
those senses to regulate each other and
那些感官互相调节和
we also use something else words right
我们也正确使用别的话
exactly and words the systems in our
准确地说出我们的系统
brains that allow us to speak and allow
让我们说话和允许的大脑
us to understand words are directly
我们直接理解单词
connected to the parts of the brainstem
连接到 脑干 的 部分
that control the body I don't mean like
控制身体，我不喜欢的意思
they're a bunch of I mean monitor I mean
他们是我的意思是监视器
monosynaptic we connected so exactly the
我们单突触连接，从而完全
same systems in your brain that are
在你的大脑同一系统是
important for you
对你很重要
to be able to understand language and to
能够 理解语言 和
speak are also directly directly
说话也直接直接
affecting the systems of your body and
影响你身体的系统和
that is why I can say something to
这 就是为什么我可以 说些什么
somebody I can speak to you and I can
有人， 我可以和你说话，我可以
have an impact on the nervous systems of
对 神经系统 产生影响
people all the way at the back of this
人们都在这 后面的 路
auditorium without they you know maybe
观众席你们不知道也许
they can see me maybe they can't maybe
他们可以看到我也许他们不可能
they can't hopefully they can't smell me
他们不能 希望他们闻不到 我的 味道
maybe they can hear me maybe they you
也许他们可以听到我，也许他们就是你
know but they can if they hear me speak
知道，但如果他们听到我说话他们就可以
words I can affect their nervous systems
我可以影响他们的神经系统
that's why a telephone works that's why
这就是为什么电话工作 的 原因
the telephone works to where you can
电话工作到你可以的地方
feel connected to someone just merely by
感到与别人只知道一味通过
hearing their voice because the sound of
听到他们的声音，因为声音
their voice has an effect on your
他们的声音对你的影响
nervous system it can it can make you
神经系统 ，它可以 让你
breathe faster it can make you breathe
呼吸更快， 它可以让你呼吸
slower and the words also have an effect
慢一点，这些话也有效果
because when I say a word like hmm I
因为当我说一句像 嗯 我
don't know
不知道
when I say word like car that's a short
当我说像汽车那样简短的话
form I have a bunch of mental features
形式我有 一堆心理特征
in my mind when I say the word car and I
当我说出汽车和我这个词时，在我的脑海里
say that word and that invokes those
说那个词和那个就是那个
similar mental features maybe not
类似的心理特征也许不是
identical but similar enough that
相同的，但足够相似
invokes it in your mind and your mind is
在你的脑海中调用它，你的思想是
made by your brain so it invokes if I
由你的大脑制造，如果我，它会调用
just say the word car there are changes
只说汽车这个词有变化
in your motor system that would be
在您的电机系统，这将是
exactly the same or very close as if you
与 你 完全相同 或非常接近
were actually in a car right so this is
实际上在 汽车右，所以这 是
something that we do and the fact we're
我们做的事情和我们的事实
attachment comes from an infant to a
依恋从婴儿到婴儿
caregiver or or to lovers or to really
看护者或或恋人或真
close friends comes from the ability
亲密的朋友来自这种能力
that we have to regulate each other's
我们 必须 相互调节的
nervous systems
神经系统
and that is why when you don't have that
这就是为什么当你没有那个
kind of attachment you die sooner on
一种执着的 你死得越快 上
average seven years sooner loneliness
寂寞平均快七年了
kills I always tell my daughter my
杀了我总是告诉我女儿我的
daughter's 19 years old I always tell
女儿 19 岁我总是 说
her you know breaking up when you break
当你休息时，她知道 分手了
up with someone it feels like it will
与某人 感觉就像它会
kill you but it won't
杀了你，但不会
loneliness however will kill you it will
然而孤独会杀了你的意思
kill you on average seven years earlier
七年前 平均杀了你
than it would if you didn't have an
比如果你没有
attachment and that's because our
附件，那是因为我们的
nervous systems you know as our bodies
神经系统， 你知道 我们的身体
got really complex through evolution and
通过进化而变得非常复杂
our brains got bigger they could only
我们的大脑变大了他们只能
get so big there are constraints on how
变得如此之大以至于如何限制
big any brain can get that have to do
任何大脑都可以做到这一点
with you know birthing the infant but it
和你一起分娩 婴儿，但它
also has to do with the metabolic cost
也与 代谢成本有关
of a brain your brain is really
大脑真的是大脑
expensive my brain really expensive
贵 我的大脑 真贵
three pounds 20 percent of your
三磅20 ％你的
metabolic budget that's a lot and so
新陈代谢预算很多
what did evolution do to solve this
进化是做什么来解决这个问题
problem well it couldn't make our brains
问题很好，它无法成为我们的大脑
any bigger so it just entrained other
任何更大的， 所以它只是夹带 其他
brains to help manage our nervous
大脑帮助管理 我们的紧张
systems so you bear the burden of other
系统让你承担 其他 的 负担
people's Alice stasis and they bury your
人们的爱丽丝停滞，他们埋葬你的
the burden of yours not always at the
你的负担并不总是在
same time but that's what it means to
同一时间，但这就是它 意味着 什么
give people support when someone when
有人的时候给予人们支持
you're feeling horrible and somebody
你感觉很恐怖，有人
Pat's you on the back or says nice words
帕特是你的背上或说好话
to you or gives you a hug they are
对你或给你 一个拥抱
physically having an effect on your body
对身体有影响
that they are helping your body to
他们正在 帮助你的身体
maintain a low stasis at a time when
在什么时候保持低瘀滞
your brain probably couldn't manage it
你的大脑可能无法管理它
on its own and so the basis of love or
靠自己 等 爱情的基础
attachment is basically that it's the
附件基本上是它的
ability to affect each other's nervous
相互影响的能力是紧张
systems in a positive way I always say
我 总是说积极的方式
to people you know the best thing for a
对于你认识最好的人来说
nervous system a human nervous system is
神经系统是人神经 系统
another human and the worst thing for a
另一个人，也是最糟糕的事情
human nerve
人的神经
system is another human because we're
系统是另一个人，因为我们是
social animals
社会动物
well beautifully put so maybe a few
非常精美，也许还有一些
questions in the audience do you mind if
在台下 你 不 介意 的问题
there's a there's microphones on both
两者都有 麦克风
sides
双方
okay sure hi thanks for talking here
好的，你好，谢谢你 在这里聊天
you're saying cool stuff not a question
你说的很酷的东西不是问题
I'll take it it's all right so I was
我会接受它， 所以我是
thinking about what you're saying about
思考你在 说什么
reward and I'm wondering first of all is
奖励，我首先想知道的是
he described as a return to a lo stasis
他描述为一回LO瘀
is reward in any way linked to the and
被奖励以任何方式联系 到和
just like the reinforcement of pathways
就像加强通路一样
or behavior so that the next time you
或行为，以便下次 你
get that stimulus you will you'll
拿到刺激你会 ，你会
respond in the same way and I'm also
以同样的方式回应， 我也是
wondering about the link between the
想知道之间的联系
desire for aloe stasis and the need for
渴望芦荟停滞和需要
novelty and then he did like a great
新奇，然后他确实像一个伟大的
it's a really great question
这是一个非常好的 问题
so um the second question is so much
所以第二个问题就是这么多
more interesting than the first actually
实际上 比第 一个更有趣
so let me say this that that there is a
所以让我说这有一个
need for novelty the need differs right
需要新奇，需要不同
for different people I will say novelty
对于不同的人，我会说新奇
so first of all the we can think about
所以首先我们可以考虑一下
the need for novelty in a really
真的需要新奇
proximal way we can think about it in a
近端的方式，我们可以想想在
really distal way like but basically
真的远端的方式，但基本上
when I say that a brain is organized or
当我说大脑是有组织的或
engineered for metabolic efficiency that
专为代谢效率而设计
doesn't mean that the goal is to to only
并不意味着目标只是为了
ever have your prediction you know your
永远有你的预测你知道你的
brains predicting all the time to always
大脑总是预测所有的时间
have its predictions completely perfect
预测完全完美
so you'll never learn nothing because
所以你永远不会学到任何东西，因为
you'll be bored out of your mind right
你会闷出 的你的头脑权
and also you know humans like to
，你也 知道人类喜欢
and their niche they like to explore so
和他们喜欢探索的利基
it's a constant balance between what
它是什么之间的不断平衡
biologists would call exploitation and
生物学家会称开发和利用
exploration novelty is is um it's
探索新奇就是它
exciting it there's actually an increase
令人兴奋的是，实际上 有所增加
in norepinephrine an increase in arousal
在去甲肾上腺素中，唤醒增加
it feels really exciting but it's also
它感觉非常 令人兴奋，但它也是
super costly novelty requires usually
通常需要超级昂贵的新奇事物
that you learn something new that means
你学到了新的东西
that's actually really metabolically
这实际上是真正的代谢
expensive thing to do and it also means
昂贵的事情要做，这也意味着
usually that you're moving your body
通常是你在移动你的身体
around which is also metabolically
周围 也是代谢的
expensive thing to do so the need for
这样做需要昂贵的东西
novelty is balanced by its cost and
新颖性由其成本和成本来平衡
different nervous systems can bear
不同的神经系统可以承受
different amounts of cost so for example
例如，不同的成本金额
if you take two rats that are somewhat
如果你服用两只有点的老鼠
genetically you know moderate like
基因上你知道温和的喜欢
they've been genetically bred one is
它们是基因繁殖的
bred when you stick it in a a novel cage
当你把它粘在一个新颖的笼子里时繁殖
it just sits still and the other one
它只是静止 而另一个
when you put it a novel cage it like
当你把它放在一个新颖的笼子里 时
roams all over the place and it's just
在整个地方漫游，这只是
you know it's going crazy kind of
你知道它真的很疯狂
exploring everything well the one that
探索一切顺利 的一个
sits still scientists might say oh
坐着， 科学家们可能会说 哦
that's a nervous rat or that rats afraid
这是一只神经过敏的老鼠或老鼠害怕的
what is that rat doing the rat is not
什么是老鼠做老鼠不是
moving and it's not encoding anything
移动，它不编码任何东西
because encoding something is expense
因为 编码是费用
it's expensive
它的价格昂贵
this rat on the other hand is roaming
该大鼠在另一方面漫游
all over the place moving a lot learning
到处都是学习的很多地方
a lot so it's encoding a lot spend spend
很多， 所以它编码了很多花费
spend save save save spend spend spend
节省开支节省开支花费
there are time there are differences
有时间有 差异
between people and there are also
人与人之间 也有
differences between times in your life
你生命中的时间差异
where moments where you feel like you
在哪里，你感觉像你
have a little bit to spend and other
有一点花和其他
moments where you feel like you really
你 真正 感觉到的那一刻
have to conserve when I talk to the
有当我交谈 的 节约
public I always talk about I don't use
公众我总是谈论 我不使用
the word out of stasis it's just too
这个词也是停滞不前的
boring a word but I sort of do is sort
无聊但我有点像是排序
of explain it like a budget you know
解释它就像你知道的预算
like your brain is sort of like the
就像你的大脑有点 像
financial office of a company a company
公司的财务办公室
has lots of offices it has to balance
有很多办公室，它必须平衡
the expenditures and revenues and it's
支出和收入就是这样
got to keep everything in balance so it
必须保持一切平衡，以便它
might take a little money here move
移动可能需要一点钱
without office you know it's got to keep
没有 办公室，你知道它必须保持
everything in balance we're just always
一切都在 平衡， 我们总是如此
trying to do is spend a little bit to
试图做的是 花一点点
make a little bit more what happens when
让多一点的时候会发生什么
it spends a little bit and it doesn't
它花了一点点而不是
get a revenue back there's no reward
获得收入后，没有奖励
what happens well it goes into the read
它会在 阅读中发生什么
a little bit so what do you do when
一点点，你什么时候做
something goes into the read well you
有些东西进入你的阅读
might do something risky you might
可能会做一些冒险的 你可能
actually spend a lot to try to really
其实花了很多尝试， 真正
may you know not just make back your
你可能知道不 只是回报你的
deficit but actually make a lot that
赤字，但实际上做了很多
would be novelty that would be move and
将是移动的新奇事物
spent moving and encode or you might
花在移动和编码上， 或者你可能
reduce your spending you might say well
减少 你可能会说 的 开支
I'm gonna save a little bit now that
我现在我会节省一点点
would be I'm not gonna move too much I'm
我会不会动起来太多了
not gonna spend too much I'm not gonna
不会花太多钱我 不会
encode anything so I certainly don't
编码任何东西所以我当然不会
mean to suggest to you that that novelty
意思是向你建议那个新奇
is unimportant or that learning is
不重要或学习是不重要的
unimportant and it's a really important
不重要，这是 非常重要的
question about what is there any
关于什么有 问题的问题
intrinsic value to novelty over and
对新奇事物的内在价值
above the rewards that it would give you
超过它会给你的回报
an analysis at ik sense but it is really
在ik意义上的分析， 但它 确实
clear to me that the extent to which you
向我明确表示你 的程度
any nervous system will embrace novelty
任何神经系统都会接受新奇事物
and even seek it pretty much depends on
甚至寻求它几乎取决于
the allostatic state of that of that
那个的全能状态
system if you don't have a lot to spend
系统， 如果你没有很多 花
and you're already in the red you if you
如果你 ，你已经 是红色的了
at a certain point if you continue to
在某一点，如果你继续
spend when you're in the red you go
你走的时候要花钱
bankrupt what that means in human terms
破产这意味着什么在人类 方面
is you get depressed it means that your
你是否感到沮丧， 这意味着你的
your brain makes you fatigued so you
你的大脑让你审美疲劳 ，所以你
can't move and it makes you locks you in
无法移动，它会让你锁定你
so you stop paying attention to anything
所以你 不要再注意任何事了
going on around you in the world and
在 世界各地和 你身边 走吧
your experience is just what's in your
你的经验正是在你的
head that that's actually what
认为这实际上是什么
depression is so that makes me think of
抑郁是让我想到 的
aloe stasis more of as a range than as a
芦荟瘀滞多为一个范围而不是一个
zero point it's not homeostasis it's
零点它不是动态平衡
Alice stasis it's a range for sure but
爱丽丝停下 来确定它是一个范围，但是
we answer some other questions and maybe
我们回答一些 其他问题， 也许
I'll get back to your first question if
如果，我会回到 你的第一个 问题
there's time so if I understand your
如果我理解你的话，那就是时候了
argument correctly if we're going to
论点正确，如果 我们要
make anything like a general
做一般的事
intelligence something
智慧的东西
approaching not like like a human it
将至不喜欢 像一个人就
needs to be an embodied system well I
需要成为一个体现的系统我
want to be careful about saying that
我要小心这么说
because for two reasons one because in
因为有两个原因， 因为 在
biology there is this concept of
生物存在 的 这一概念
degeneracy just a sucky word but it's a
堕落只是一个蹩脚的词，但它是一个
great concept and it means that there's
伟大的概念， 它意味着 有
more than one way to skin a cat
对皮肤有猫 的 方法不止一种
basically you want a functional outcome
基本上你想要一个功能性的结果
there are many ways to get to that
有很多方法可以 解决 这个问题
functional outcome so genes for example
功能结果如此基因
you know there are a lot of
你知道有很多
characteristics that are heritable but
可遗传的特征但是
we don't know the genes for them and the
我们不知道他们和他们的基因
reason why is that there isn't one set
之所以没有 一套
of genes there are like multiple sets of
基因有多套
genes that can give you actually the
实际上可以给你的基因
same outcome so what I want to say is
同样的结果所以我想说的是
that you need something akin to a body
你需要类似于身体的东西
it doesn't actually have to be a body I
它实际上并不 一定是 一个 我 的身体
imagine there are lots of ways that you
想象有很多方法 ， 你
could implement a system you could
可以实现你可以的系统
implement an agent that has multiple
实现具有多个的代理
systems of some sort that it has to
某种系统 ，它具有
manage but my point is that one thing
管理， 但我的观点是一件事
about that is very important that we
这 对 我们 来说 非常重要
continually miss when we think about
我们想到的时候不断错过
building an agent with mental states we
建立一个心理状态的代理人我们
continually miss the fact that it has a
不断错过它有一个事实
body it has about humans have bodies and
身体它有关于人类有身体和
that's the brains primary task and our
这是大脑的首要任务和我们的
most fundamental feelings come from the
最根本的感受来自 于
physical changes in our body even though
尽管身体发生了变化
we don't normally experience it that way
我们通常不会这样经历
that actually is how it is if you just
实际上，如果你只是如此
look at the wiring of the brain if you
如果你 看看 大脑 的接线
just see it so it seems to me that if
只是看到它，所以在我看来，如果
you want to build an agent that is human
你想建立是 人类 代理
like it has to have something like a
喜欢 它必须有 类似的 东西
body doesn't have to maybe be a body and
身体不一定是身体和
I'm sure there are many clever ways that
我确信有很多聪明的方法
you could implement something like a
你可以实现类似 的 东西
body without it actually being a body if
身体没有它实际上是一个身体，如果
you know if you understand what I mean
你知道，如果你明白我的意思
so Amazon Alexa could be there if we
所以亚马逊Alexa可能会在那里，如果我们
just gave it some sort of I don't know
只是给了它 一些 我不知道的东西
representation of mental states or some
代表心理状态或某些
kind of a low static yeah target sure
一种低静态耶的目标肯定
here's just say one other thing because
这里只说另一件事，因为
I think it's really important all a
我认为 这 一切都非常重要
brain requires is that you at some point
大脑需要的是你 在某个时刻
had a body you know right so basically
有一个你基本知道的身体
being this is what phantom limb pain is
是这是幻肢痛 是 什么
this is what chronic pain is this is
这就是慢性 疼痛 是，这是
what happened you know if at some point
如果在某个时刻你知道怎么回事
you cease to get information from your
你 停止 从 你的 信息 中 获取信息
body anymore your brain still can
你的大脑仍然可以
simulate still can reinstate the sensory
模拟仍然可以恢复感官
patterns that once came from the body
曾经来自身体的图案
and that's what's required right at some
这 就是某些人所要求的
point the body isn't really needed
指出身体并不是真的需要
anymore yeah I think we're here yeah so
是的， 我想我们在这里 是的
emotions in humans Lucas are they
人类的情感卢卡斯是他们
implemented by a bunch of hacks so
一帮黑客如此实施
there's a bunch of chemicals that go
还有一大堆的去 化学品
into your brain those oxytocin serotonin
进入你的大脑那些催产素5-羟色胺
a whole bunch of biochemical things that
一大堆生物化学的东西
diffuse around in the fluids in your
弥漫在你体内的液体中
brain that affect your emotional state
影响你 情绪状态的大脑
and that seems like a Hank that we've
而这似乎 是我们 的 汉克
inherited over millions of years from
从数百万年继承而来
premature ancestors and if you look at
过早的祖先，如果你看看
the machine learning world we can do a
我们可以做的机器学习世界
bunch of similar things with you on that
你身上 有很多类似的东西
so you can increase the activation
所以你 可以增加激活
thresholds on a large scale you have
你有大规模的门槛
changed the map noise going into the
改变了地图噪音进入
system you can do a bunch of similar
系统你 可以做一堆 类似的
things but you don't have to rely on
事情， 但你不必 依赖
fluids being kind of cleaned slowly by
流体是一种缓慢清洗的
glial cells things don't diffuse around
神经胶质细胞不会扩散到 周围
in and fluid in the system necessarily
必须在系统内和流体中
seems like there's a lot more
好像还有更多
flexibility so when you come to an
灵活性所以当你来到一个
implementation there's not so many
实施没有那么多
constraints imposed by the evolutionary
进化所施加的限制
history on the whole system and it seems
似乎 整个 系统的 历史
like that would make it work better so
这样将 使其更好地工作 ，以便
when people are in negative emotional
当人们处于负面情绪状态时
states and they can't think straight
国家，他们不能直接思考
people can think actually quite well a
人们实际上可以认为相当好 一个
negative emotional state they don't tell
消极的情绪状态，他们 没有告诉
you so but they can play with crimes
你这样，但他们可以玩犯罪
they can do very nefarious things very
他们可以做非常邪恶的 事情
very effectively right so but the
非常有效，但是
general point I think is true even if
总的来说， 即使我认为也是如此
that example is not so emotions kind of
这个例子是 不是这样的情绪样 的
flood your nervous system without
没有你的神经系统
emotions don't flood your nervousness
情绪不会让你紧张不安
all right so some of them do so now
好的， 所以有些 人 现在 就这样做 了
perfectly of yes sir
完美的是先生
you thing in your bloodstream let's talk
你 血液中的东西让我们谈谈吧
about this chemical let's talk about
关于这种化学物质让我们来谈谈
this chemical there's not a single
这种化学物质没有一个
chemical in your brain or anywhere in
化学物质在你的大脑 或任何地方
your nervous system that is for emotion
你的神经 系统是情感的
serotonin is not for emotion don't mean
血清素不是为情感而不是意味着
it's not for emotion oxytocin is not for
它不是因为情感催产素不适合
emotion well even opioid you know even
你甚至知道甚至是阿片类药物
even Opie even opioids are not for
甚至Opie甚至阿片类药物也不适合
emotion so they influence your emotions
情绪， 所以他们影响你的情绪
they're involved they influence every
他们参与其中影响每一个人
mental event that you have not just
你不仅仅是心理事件
emotion so your brain for example your
情绪， 所以你的大脑，例如 你的
brain is a physical it's a set of
大脑是一种物理它是一组
physical cells that are bathed in neuro
沐浴在神经中的物理细胞
chemical systems and the neuro chemical
化学系统和神经化学
systems that you're referring to
你所指的系统
basically change the ease with which
基本上改变了易用性
information is passed back and forth
信息来回 传递
between those neurons that's always true
在那些永远是真实的神经元之间
it's true regardless of whether the
无论是否真的都是如此
event is a motion or whether it's a
事件是动议还是动作
perception or whether it's a thought or
感知或是否是一个思想或
whether it's a belief it's always true
是否一种信念 总是如此
so for example serotonin serotonin is a
因此， 例如血清素血清素是一个
neurotransmitter that allows your brain
允许你的大脑的神经递质
to delay gratification of a reward it
延迟奖励 它的满足感
allows you to expend energy now because
允许你现在消耗能量，因为
you anticipate a reward at some point in
你期待在某个时刻 获得奖励
the future and if you have a deficit in
未来，如果你有赤字
serotonin then you can't do that very
5-羟色胺然后你不能这样做
well and it turns out for humans one of
好吧，它结果 是人类之一
our great superpowers is the ability to
我们伟大的超级大国才有能力
do mental time travel to remember in the
精神时间旅行要记住
past and also to do things now because
过去也是为了现在做事，因为
we know they're going to have an effect
我们知道它们会产生影响
ten or twenty or fifty or a hundred
十或 二十或 五十或 一百
years from now so the the you know in
从现在起几年， 你知道的
when I said you have to have something
当我说你必须要有东西的时候
like a body I'm not saying literally you
像一个身体，我不是 字面意思你
have to have a physical corporeal body
必须有一个肉体的身体
I'm saying you have to have you I mean
我说你必须 拥有我的意思
it's just a fact it's not an argument
这只是一个事实， 它不是一个论点
it's a fact that your brain that brains
这是一个事实，你的大脑 是大脑
evolved for the purposes of regulating
为了规范的目的而进化
multiple systems and from a cybernetics
多个系统和 控制论
standpoint you know the best way to
你知道最好的方法
regulate a system is to build an
规范一个系统是建立一个
internal model of it that's what your
它的内部模型就是你的
brain is your brain is an internal model
大脑是你的大脑是内部模型
of your body in the world it's running
在你正在运行的世界中你的身体
simulations it's running this model and
模拟它正在运行这个模型和
if you want to have an age
如果你想要一个年龄
that is somewhat human-like that has
这是有些人一样 ，没有
feelings like humans then they have to
然后他们必须像人类一样感受
do something that they have to have to
做一些 他们必须要做的事情
be able to do something similar and
可以 做类似的东西
whether it's a actually physical
它是否 真的是物理的
corporeal body or not I think is you
身体与否我认为是你
know that's an open question right so it
我知道这是一个公开的问题
sounds a bit as though you're disputing
听起来有点像你在争论
my premises before I got to my question
在 我提出问题 之前我的前提
so I started off by saying sorry I
所以我开始 说对不起我
started off by saying emotions are
开始说 情绪
implemented as a bunch of hacks so would
实现了一堆黑客， 所以会
you say that was rub broadly correct or
你说这是大致正确的或
would you say that they're not hacks
你会说他们不是黑客吗？
they're finely tuned and adaptive and
他们精心调整和适应性
well I went there not maladaptive but
好吧，我去那里不是适应不良但是
would you say it's a bunch of hacks I
你会说这是一帮黑客的 我
don't think I don't know what you mean
不要以为我不知道你的意思
by hacks
黑客攻击
I think luge's kind of historical
我觉得雪橇的历史
accidents I think they're wrong you're
事故我认为他们错了你
talking about emotions like they're
谈论他们的情绪
they're talking the the premise of your
他们说的 是你的前提
question I can't answer your question
问题我无法回答你的问题
because I think it's not the correct
因为我 认为这不正确
question I mean what its emotions aren't
问题 我的意思是 它的情绪不是
like blood pressure you know they don't
像血压， 你 知道他们没有
exist in that sense they are they are
从这个意义上讲，他们 就是这样
the way that they are first of all not
他们首先 是 没有办法的办法
all cultures have not all people in all
所有文化都不 是所有人
cultures have emotions
文化有情感
everybody has effect assuming they have
假设有人，每个人都有效
a neurotypical brain of sorts but but
一种神经典型的大脑，但是
they don't all have emotion and so to
他们并不都有感情，所以
answer your question that your answer
回答你的问题， 你的答案
asking me is I can't answer because I
问我是不能回答因为我
don't think it's the right I don't think
不认为这是我没想到的权利
it's the right opioids and the the pain
这是 正确的阿片类药物和疼痛
systems seem like things that influence
系统看起来 像影响的东西
your emotions fairly directly so this
你的情绪直接如此
it's not that it's the same thing but
这并不是说这是同样的事情 ，但
it's that there's a powerful link
这是一个强大的 链接
opioids though so opioids are important
阿片类药物虽然如此，阿片类药物很重要
for instances of emotion but they are
对于情感的例子， 但他们是
also important for every other category
对其他所有类别都很重要
of mental event that you brain can make
你大脑可以做的心理事件
other things too I agree so I you know
其他事情 我也同意所以我知道
but you will see sometimes scientists
但有时你会看到科学家
will assign you know I'm an emotional
会告诉你 我 知道 我是情绪化的
meaning to something like dopamine is
对 多巴胺这样的 意思 是
for you know first hedonic pleasantness
因为你知道第一个享乐的愉快
and then it's for reward people like to
然后它是为了奖励人们喜欢的
assign
分配
single functions two biological entities
单一功能两个 生物实体
like a chemical or a brain region a
像化学物质或大脑区域
cluster of neurons or it's just not
神经元簇或它不是
that's really I'm not saying every
那真的我不是每个人都说的
chemical does everything but whatever
化学品做的一切，除了任
whatever opioids do they do in every
他们做的每一种阿片类药物都是如此
waking moment of your life not just in
你生命中醒来的时刻不仅仅是在
moments that are emotional for you
对你来说很有情感的时刻
I should stop thank you very much yep I
我应该停止非常感谢你 是的我
think it is very interesting that you
认为你很有意思
brought up the last topic of love
提出了爱的最后一个话题
because I think it actually brings up a
因为我认为它实际上 会带来 一个
really important thing which is and what
真正重要的 是什么
you were saying about connection that's
你说有关连接这
I mean the primary purpose of life is to
我的意思是生命的主要目的是
procreate right I mean that that's what
生育正确我的意思 是那是什么
our genes do so first of all right I'm
我们的基因首先这样做，我是
not gonna be touching that yeah so yeah
不会再 被触及 的是 耶所以是
and and it's of course in humans it's
它当然是人类的
not just genetic it's mimetic I mean we
不只是遗传它是 模仿我的意思是我们
appropriated our ideas as well as you
和你一样挪用我们的想法
know physically and so a primary purpose
了解身体，因此是一个主要 目的
of our wanting our our reactions and
我们想要我们的反应和
interactions with other people and other
与其他 人和 其他 人的互动
things is that goal is that we get
事情是 我们得到的目标
rewarded when we interact with other
当我们与其他人互动时获得奖励
things in a way that creates something
事物以创造某种东西的方式
new whether it's art or you know a book
新的无论是艺术还是你懂一本书
or technology or something like that
或技术或类似的东西
and if we don't put that if there's no
如果我们不这样做， 如果没有
inherent reason for a robot or a
机器人或机器人的固有原因
computer system to want to do that I
计算机系统 想要那样做我
mean how do we how can we can even
意味着我们怎么能够均匀
imagine
想像
putting that into a system inherently
把它固有地放入系统中
that it wants to that it just
它 只是 想它
desperately wants to make something new
拼命想要创造新事物
I mean well here's what I would say you
我的意思是，这就是我要说的
know when we're we're first of all we're
知道我们什么时候才是我们的首要任务
not we talk about we've been focusing a
我们不是在 谈论我们一直在关注的问题
lot on bodies I'm certainly not saying
在身体上很多我当然不会说
that's a sufficient condition right I'm
对我来说这是一个充分的 条件
just saying it's a
只是 说它是一个
Ceri one or something like a body but I
Ceri 一个或 类似 身体但 我
certainly have the motivation to create
当然有创造的动力
and I'm imagining that you do too I have
和我想象你也这样做我 有
to tell you not everybody has that most
告诉你 不是每个人都有 这个
adolescents don't have that many
青少年没有 那么多
adolescents don't have it okay that was
青少年没有 它没关系
a joke I have a teenage daughter I'm
一个笑话 我有一个十几岁的女儿我
just telling you yeah but the point is
只是告诉你是的但 重点 是
that that what people what people find
这是人们发现的人
rewarding is is remarkably diverse but
奖励是非常多样化但是
the property I think is that there has
我认为的财产是有的
to be a feature of reward for for a lot
成为很多奖励的一个特征
of people that's you know that's having
那些你知道的人
an impact in some way having an impact
以某种方式产生影响的影响
on another person having an impact you
对另一个影响 你的人
know on a building something that wasn't
知道 建筑物上 没有的 东西
there before whatever you know in in
在 你所知道的 之前
innovating or I'm discovering but it's
创新或我发现 但是它
not true for everybody it's just true
不是每个人都是如此， 这是真的
for like a lot of people in this room
对于像 这个房间里 的很多 人 一样
probably and certainly the people that
可能而且肯定是那个人
we probably spend a lot of time with but
我们可能会花很多时间，但是
not not for everybody
不是每个人都不是
sure I mean look but if you want to you
我的意思是看， 但如果你想要你
know if you want to if you you know we
如果你了解我们就知道你是否愿意
can certainly make a kinetic argument
当然可以做出 动力学论证
here absolutely
这绝对是
there there the there's nothing that
那里 没有什么
I've said today that is inconsistent
我今天说过这是不一致的
with the idea that that you have to that
我认为 你必须这样做
you have to pass your genes on to the
你必须将你的基因传递 给
next generation and actually make sure
下一代，实际上确保
that that generation survives to
这一代人幸存下来
reproductive age it's not just enough to
生育年龄不仅仅是足够的
have offspring you have to make sure the
有后代 ，你必须确保
offspring survive to reproductive age
后代存活到生育年龄
and there's a whole argument about you
关于 你 ，有一个完整的 争论
know the the learning of social reality
了解社会现实的学习
concepts of social reality that we've
我们的社会现实概念
been talking about like money and
在谈论 喜欢钱 和
emotions and so on that makes that
情绪等，使该
argument right that it's very expensive
争论 说它 非常昂贵
to have to encode everything in jeans or
必须用牛仔裤或牛仔裤编码所有东西
to have to learn everything from scratch
必须从头学习一切
every generation so instead what we have
我们所拥有的每一代都是如此
is a system a genetic system that allows
是一个允许的遗传系统系统
us to wire the brains of the young with
我们用年轻人的大脑连接 起来
what we know and that's what we do
我们所知道的，这就是我们所做的
basically right so it's the I'm curious
基本上是正确的，所以我很好奇
about your analogy about intentionality
关于你对意向性的类比
that you talked about when you use the
你在谈论使用时谈到的
analogy between money and the perception
金钱与感知之间的类比
of red to the facts that we the fact
红色的事实是我们的事实
that we have emotion because the
因为我们有情感
distinguishing feature it seems to me is
在我看来，区别特征是
the level of intentionality and as you
意向性的程度和你一样
said before our brain assigns meaning to
在我们的 大脑赋予意义 之前说过
things but we don't or maybe and and my
事情，但我们没有或可能 和我的
question is whether or not you agree
问题是你是否同意
with this I guess we don't always
有了这个，我想我们并不总是这样
deliberately assign me nothing I've said
刻意地指责我， 我已经 说过了
is about ever deliberate but sometimes
是故意但有时
we do write often actually yeah so when
我们经常写，实际上 是的， 所以当
you go back to like the question of what
你回去 喜欢 什么的问题
makes something intelligent a lot of
使智能 很多
previous talks have been about you know
以前的会谈是 关于你知道的
we want to pick a goal and then we
我们想选择一个目标然后我们
create costs to achieve that goal but
为实现这一 目标创造成本 但是
that goal is deliberately if assigned so
如果分配的话，这个目标是故意的
when you talk about like what makes
当你谈论的是什么使
something intelligent what do you think
聪明的事你觉得怎么样？
the role of intentionality is and the
意向性的作用是和
spectrum therein so first of all we talk
其中的频谱首先 我们谈谈
about intentionality I think you have to
关于我认为你必须的意向性
really be careful that you are
真的要 小心你
philosophers talk about intentionality
哲学家谈论意向性
in two ways they talk about
他们谈论两种方式
intentionality to mean a deliberate
故意意味着蓄意
action the way you mean it but
以你的意思行事 但是
intentionality can also mean that
意向也意味着
something has a referent out in the real
某些东西在真实中具有指称性
we're out and outside of you really so
我们出去和你外面真的如此
that a word a word has a referent that's
一个单词有一个单词有一个指示对象
the you know the intention of the of the
你知道 的意图
word basically I think you have to be
这个词基本上我 认为你必须是
really careful I also think that you
真的很小心我也认为你
have to make a distinction between a
必须区分a
conscious deliberate explicitly a goal
有意识地明确目标
that you can explicitly describe and I
你 可以明确地描述和我
mean you're you're sort of making you're
意味着你是在做你自己
sort of making I mean wait the kind of
我的意思是 等待那种
question you're asking is getting very
你问的问题变得非常好
close to the question of free will so I
接近 自由意志的问题所以我
would love to not have
我不想 拥有
disgust but but basically okay and and I
厌恶，但基本上 没关系，而且 我
what I'm about to say is gonna sound
我 要说的就是听起来
very Cartesian unfortunately because
非常笛卡尔因为
that's English I don't know there's no
那是英文， 我不知道有没有
other way to do it actually but what I
其他 方式实际上， 但我
want to say is that your brain is always
我想说的是你的大脑永远都是
there is always a volition but it's not
总是有意志，但 事实并非如此
always consciously experienced by you as
总是有意识地经历过你
as agency or will so yeah you're not
作为代理或将如此，是的， 你不是
you're not a sea urchin you know your
你不是一个海胆， 你知道你的
sensory neurons are not hardwired to
感觉神经元不是硬连线的
your motor neurons you have inter
你的运动神经元你有
neurons that means you have choice do
神经元意味着你有选择吗
you consciously experience yourself as
你有意识地体验自己
making choices all the time no you don't
不断做出选择
but your brain is actually making
但是你的大脑实际上正在制造
choices all the time that's why people
所有 时间 的 选择都是 人们的原因
who study decision making you know think
研究决策的人 你知道吗
they're studying the whole brain because
他们正在研究 整个大脑，因为
they they are actually so I think you
他们实际上是我认为你
have to be really careful about there
必须非常小心 ， 有
are words that we use in English and in
是我们在英语和英语中使用的单词
science that have two meanings they can
科学有两个方面的含义，他们可以
have a meaning that is about decision
有一个关于决定的意义
making or choice that is just obligatory
做出或选择只是强制性的
automatic and a function of how the
自动和功能如何
system works and then there's the kind
系统工作 ，那就是那种
of choice that feels deliberate and
选择 感觉有意和
effortful and where we feel like we're
努力，我们觉得 我们在哪里
the agents we experience ourselves as
我们体验自己的代理商
the agents and intentionality usually
通常是代理人和意向性
can be assigned to the second one but
可以分配给 第二个但是
actually in truth in philosophical terms
其实在哲学术语真相
it can also be assigned to the first
它也可以 分配给第一个
that when you even if you're completely
当你即使你完全是你的时候
unaware of having made a choice you're
没有意识到你做出了选择
acting on something with some degree of
在某种程度上做某事
volition because you you it's not a
意志，因为你，你这不是
reflex it's not like you know somebody
反射它不像你认识的人
hit your patellar tendon and nuke it and
击中你的髌骨肌腱并将其核对
so it's really interesting so you know I
所以它真的很有趣所以你知道我
think you just have to you have to make
认为你 必须要做
that distinction and I probably should
这种区别， 我可能应该
get to the next question we can question
到达 我们可以 质疑 下一个 问题
yeah thank you yep yeah so you've been
是的，谢谢你， 是的， 所以你 去过
asked a lot of esoteric questions about
问了很多深奥的问题
AI but I think we might gain some
人工智能， 但我想我们可能会获得 一些
insights by wondering about di that is a
通过想知道di的见解
dog intelligence oh sure
狗的智力哦，当然
so I believe I sort of understand what
所以我相信我有点理解
my dog is feeling and III usually
我的狗通常是感觉和III
believe that my dog you know believes
相信我认识的我的狗相信
the same but not the same with you know
与你知道的相同但不一样
a cat because you're not a cat person
一只猫， 因为你不是一个猫人
yeah sure I mean you know I'm not I
是的， 我 确定 我的意思是 你知道我 不是我
don't know that much about monkeys but
不 很了解 ，但 猴子
I've never really seen a monkey be able
我从来没有真正见过猴子能够
to make the expressions that let's say a
做出让我们说的表达式
dog can and I was wondering if you had
狗 可以 ，我想知道你有没有
any insights about you know why dogs are
任何关于你的见解都知道为什么是 狗
able to do this and why we're able to
能够 做到这一点 ，为什么我们能够做到
read dogs is it something just simple
读狗是一件 简单的 事情
like they're they have the right facial
就像 他们 有正确的面部护理一样
muscles or is it something some drive
肌肉或是一些 驱动器
that allows them to learn this so I
这让我们学习这个，所以我
think before I wrote my book I would
在我写我的书之前，我想
have answered this question differently
以不同方式回答了这个问题
but now here's what I would say I think
但 现在这就是我 想的
what you know many creatures on this
你知道很多生物吗？
planet have effect right and we can
行星有效 ，我们可以
debate about whether you know I just
关于 你是否知道我的辩论
came across a paper the other day about
横跨纸那天 约来到
whether fly you know just your Safa I
是否飞行你只知道你的萨法我
have have effect and you know it's I
有效果，你知道这是我
mean it's actually really interesting
意味着它真的 很 有趣
question they certainly they have
他们当然有问题
something like opioids and they you know
像阿片类药物，你知道吗？
so it's consistory question but dogs
所以它的 consistory 问题，但狗
dogs are really interesting because they
狗真的很有趣，因为它们
do seem to have some capacities that
似乎有一些能力
only that you only see in in great apes
只有你只能看到类人猿
and they may have capacities that great
他们的能力可能很大
apes even other than us don't have and I
甚至 我们以外的猿都没有 和我
mean so they certainly have some
意思是所以他们肯定有一些
capacities we don't have either but but
我们没有的能力，但是
here's my point
这是我的观点
we actually bred them we bred these
我们实际上培育了它们，我们培育了这些
animals we selected them basically it's
我们 基本上 选择它们的动物
not natural selection it's it's you know
不是自然选择它是你知道的
artificial selection and we selected
人工选择我们选择
them for a couple of things right if you
如果你，他们可以做 几件事
look at the experiments on breeding
看看育种实验
taking a fox you know taking foxes and
采取狐狸 你知道服用狐狸 和
breeding them into what looked like
将它们培育成看起来像的东西
little dog like animals it's interesting
像动物一样的小狗很有意思
what they can do and one of the things
他们能做什么和其中一件事
they can do is they can move their
他们能做的就是他们可以移动他们的
facial muscles and in in in a lot of
面部肌肉和 很多
ways that they have a lot more control
他们有更多 控制权的方式
over their facial muscles then you know
你了解 面部 肌肉
chimpanzees and
黑猩猩和
do and and other apes and they also do
做和其他类 人猿，他们也做
they do joint attention really well with
他们非常关注
gays so this is something that really no
同性恋，所以这是真的没有
other animal can do I think other than a
其他动物可以做我认为的 除了
dog other and humans and that is they
狗其他和人类，那 就是他们
can they they meet your gaze and they
他们能满足你的目光吗？
use gaze for reference so you know
使用凝视作为参考， 所以 你知道
they'll look at something and they'll
他们会看一些东西而且 他们会
look back at you and you you know that's
回头看看你， 你知道那是
actually partly that's how we
实际上部分是我们的方式
communicate with each other chimpanzees
相互通信 的黑猩猩
lose that ability after about ten or
大约十或之后失去这种能力
eleven months a year overall of age but
一年十一个月的整体年龄 但是
but dogs continually do it and actually
但狗不断地做，实际上
joint attention shared gaze is how we
共同关注共同凝视是我们如何
communicate with our infants also that's
与我们的 婴儿 沟通 也是如此
actually partly how we teach infants
实际上我们是如何教婴儿的
about what's important in the world is
关于世界上最重要的是什么
with gaze so I think that dogs may
凝视所以我认为狗可能
actually have some capacities probably
实际上可能有一些能力
because we bred them to have those but
因为我们培育他们有那些但是
we selected the animals that you know
我们选择 了你 知道 的动物
and bred them to have those capacities
并培养他们拥有这些能力
that's very interesting again awesome
这是非常有趣的再次 真棒
well with that let's give these a big
好吧，让我们给这些一个大
hand thank you so much
亲爱的，非常感谢你